let me let me start this way so I have a
Ministry another Ministry called Army
Bible camp and army Bible Camp I started
it um probably about 10 years ago now um
and it was because people kept asking me
Pastor how do you study the Bible how
did you see that how did you get that
out I've read that story like a hundred
times we've heard your sermon so we yeah
we know and we say that on salvation and
symbols and signs too where did how did
you I've read the same scripture over
and over again but where did this
Insight come from besides obviously the
Holy Spirit but how did you come to that
yeah so you know when people would ask
me I would never you know I never had an
answer ready for them like it was just
like well that's just how to study the
Bible you know and when people started
asking me more and more I was like you
know what I need to like I need to think
about what I'm doing like how am I going
through this process and this is the
process that led me to this system
called photo theology right the study uh
of the of of God through the use of
pictures
um one of the and there are many
different principles in this
system but let me I'm going to share a
statement with you um and I'm going to
see what what comes to your mind when I
share this statement so uh it's taken
from review and Herald April 16th uh
1889 and here's what it says it says
take your Bible
and compare passage with passage and
verse with verse and you will find the
precious jewels of
Truth you should put the precious gems
of light in a beautiful setting and hang
them in memory's
Hall that's a
quote what came to your mind when I read
that a picture okay what kind of a
picture um hang them in memories Hall
yeah did did you did you see
Association did you see I don't know
about you I see hooks I I see a hall
memories Hall memories Hall that brings
to my mind a picture right now I'm
seeing a hall in my mind so I'm I'm a
visual person I'm seeing aaall I'm a
person that likes pictures right so I'm
seeing a hul in my mind and I'm being
told that I should take
different truths different stories in
the Bible and hang them in memor hall
now um the this system of of Bible study
that I have photo theology so I'm now
doing uh I'm now training people this is
how you you you do this right so like I
said it's an entire system and one of
the first things I share is this concept
of memories Hall so when I was younger
there was a card game I used to play
called concentration oh yeah name
concentration all the cards are facing
down and you turn one card and then you
have to find the matching card right and
you got to remember where did I see that
card before where did I and so you flip
you flip Ah that's a match right in
essence that is the art of Bible study
that is the art of photo theology so
let's play
Concentration okay I'm going to give you
a
picture Moses goes on top of a mountain
he tells
Joshua you're fighting the amalekites
below you fight I'm going to go up to
the Mountaintop and when I lift my hands
with the rod when I lift my
hands when I lift my hands with the rod
in my hand you're going to experience
Victory when I lift my hands
when I lift my
hands when my hands are connected to
Wood and I have lifted my hands you're
going to experience Victory yes every
time his hands come down no Victory
every time his hands go up wow those
hands are connected to the rod to Wood
there is Victory now you're saying wow
and I'm you know I I haven't said
anything I'm just giving you a story I
have the picture okay so now the
pictures is not complete because
remember Moses's hands begin to get
tired so Aaron stands on one side of him
her stands on the other side of him
Moses is is on a
rock huh his hands are extended
connected to Wood on either side of him
is Aaron and her and they are holding
his hands up wow now you're saying wow
and I haven't all I have done is giving
you a pcture of a story you already know
yes okay but something just happened cuz
as I was explaining that story you were
saying hold on hold on wait a minute
wait a minute and what ends up happening
you ran down memor Hall and you were
like I've seen that picture someplace
else and then you're like hold on wait a
minute and what are you thinking you
tell me what you why are you smiling
maybe why don't you tell our viewers why
you're smiling oh because you can see
Jesus on the cross right with his arms
outstretched between the two thieves
that's right yeah and now we know that
because of those hands that were
extended on the cross we can have
victory in our
fight oh that's good see I've never seen
that before that's we can have victory
in our fight that's right that's why we
have victory in our battle against the
Flesh and our battle against you know
the principalities of this world because
because of what Christ did on the cross
and now I know something else too from
this story it's not the nails that held
his hands up that's right it was The
Sinner on either side of him that held
his hands up just as Aaron and her stood
there to hold up Moses's hands it was
The Sinner on either side of him in
other words Jesus died for the whole
world those that would accept him and
those that would reject him yes embodied
in those two thieves on the cross
and so what have we just done we just
played a game the game is called
concentration whoa I see this story in
the Bible and I'm trying to I'm learning
how to think in
pictures that's all we just did like if
you had a sermon to preach now and no
one ever watched this you could be like
hey you know what I'm going to preach or
and they'll be like what Jason how did
you see
that right don't be surprised you go I
won't preach at a church where you
preach don't worry but that's that's
that's photo theology right it's a
simple art of having these pictures in
your mind and then learning how to match
the pictures how to connect the pictures
to reveal a story